James White

Address: Hemel Hempstead, Hertfordshire (Willing to relocate)

Mobile: 07905294111 Email: jamesw.white96@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/jamesw-white/ Website: jwhite42.com

Profile:

A Cloud Specialist and Cyber Security graduate who has experience working with the Cloud including AWS, Azure and GCP. Certified AWS Solutions Architect Associate with a strong knowledge of Cloud based services, Infrastructure as Code (IaC) and configuration management tools. Over nine years' experience in the logistics industry, gaining valuable transferable skills in team leading, relationship building and project management. Strong track record of quick learning and adapting to new complex situations. Committed to personal learning and development.

Key Skills:

- Cloud Computing Experience building solutions in the Cloud including AWS, Azure and GCP. Strong knowledge of EC2, VPC, IAM, S3, RDS and CloudFront.
- Infrastructure as Code Capable of building and managing Cloud infrastructure using CloudFormation and Terraform.
- Server Administration Administrating and troubleshooting Linux and Windows servers including configuration automation tools such as Ansible, Puppet and Chef.
- **Programming** Proficient in **Python** and **JavaScript** including web application development as well as using technologies such as **Django** and **React**.
- Databases Working knowledge of Amazon Aurora, DynamoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Work Experience:

Cloud Specialist - go deploy (Sept 2021 - Present)

- Creating learning labs for hands-on IT and Cloud based training for instructors and individuals.
- Building underlying infrastructure to support lab environments using various Cloud platforms and HyperV.
- Developing new content and collaborating with other teams to create the best possible learning materials.
- Implementing AWS and GCP IAM permissions policies to ensure lab environments adhere to least privilege best practices.
- Maintaining and testing learning labs for the current system as well as before the deployment of the new live system.

Transport Planner - Igloo Thermo Logistics (July 2015 – Sept 2021)

Transport Coordinator - Aalco Metals (June 2013 – April 2015)

Education:

University of Plymouth (2017–2021)

- BSc. (Hons) Cyber Security First Class Honours
- Foundation Year, Computing (2017 2018)

Certifications:

- AWS Certified Solutions Architect Associate
- HashiCorp Certified Terraform Associate
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner
- Microsoft Certified Azure Fundamentals
- Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician (CCENT)